<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Career on Muhammad Azeez</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/career/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Career on Muhammad Azeez</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 08 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/career/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Working remotely from Iraq as a Software Developer</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/working-remotely-from-iraq/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/working-remotely-from-iraq/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Disclaimer:&lt;/strong&gt; I am writing about my personal experience here. Your mileage may vary.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I have been working remotely for a European company since the beginning of the year. I have been through a lot of ups and downs since then, I want to document some of the insights I learned.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Working remotely among the tech community is getting more and more common right now in Iraq. I have several friends who work for companies in Europe and other places. Most of the pre-requisites of working remotely are available in Iraq and Kurdistan, even though they are not as convenient as one might hope, so I think more software developers should consider it as an option.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why you should read on topics that you might not need right now?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/why-you-should-read-on-topics-that-you-might-not-need-right-now/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/why-you-should-read-on-topics-that-you-might-not-need-right-now/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I was browsing web once when I stumbled upon an article about &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/mono/SkiaSharp&#34;&gt;SkiaSharp&lt;/a&gt;. It&amp;rsquo;s a C# wrapper around Google&amp;rsquo;s fast 2D rending engine. I was developing desktop apps in WPF at the time and didn&amp;rsquo;t feel the need to learn a low level library like that.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A few weeks later, I found myself in a project that required building a fast layout designer. First, I tried to write it purely in WPF, and I did. It was super slow, on a decently fast computer, it took a few seconds to load a layout.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
