<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Uwp on Muhammad Azeez</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/uwp/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Uwp on Muhammad Azeez</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 25 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/uwp/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>&#39;Enabling automatic updates for sideloaded UWP apps: Multiple update channels&#39;</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/update-sideloaded-uwp-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/update-sideloaded-uwp-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In a &lt;a href=&#34;https://mazeez.dev/posts/update-sideloaded-uwp&#34;&gt;previous&lt;/a&gt; post we talked about getting more control over the update process in sideloaded UWP apps. And in &lt;a href=&#34;https://mazeez.dev/posts/uwp-devops&#34;&gt;another post&lt;/a&gt; we talked about setting up CI/CD pipelines for UWP apps. This time we will talk about how to create multiple update channels, i.e. alpha, beta, stable, for our UWP app.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The idea is very simple, and although I am going to use Azure Blob Storage, nothing stops you from using a normal web host.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Setting up automated build and release pipeline for side-loaded UWP apps using Azure DevOps</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/uwp-devops/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/uwp-devops/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This week we set up a CI/CD pipeline for one of our UWP apps that needs to be sideloaded because we don&amp;rsquo;t publish it through the Microsoft Store. &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/windows/uwp/packaging/auto-build-package-uwp-apps&#34;&gt;This article&lt;/a&gt; was super useful in getting me started. Microsoft has made things quite easy with Azure DevOps, but there were a few things that took us a little bit of time to figure out.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-little-bit-of-context&#34;&gt;A little bit of context&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We have an enterprise UWP application that we publish via an http server. We also have a custom auto-update mechanism that updates the apps whenever an update is available. You can learn more about the &lt;a href=&#34;https://mazeez.dev/posts/update-sideloaded-uwp&#34;&gt;auto-updater here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to get an instance of a page when you navigate to it in UWP</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/how-to-get-an-instance-of-a-page-when-you-navigate-to-it-in-uwp/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/how-to-get-an-instance-of-a-page-when-you-navigate-to-it-in-uwp/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;By default when navigating a frame to a page, UWP doesn&amp;rsquo;t give you back a page instance. So the only way of passing parameters is to use the &lt;code&gt;parameter&lt;/code&gt; parameter. But having an instance to the page can have many other benefits: For example it allows the child page to have custom events and the parent page can subscribe to them.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;However &lt;code&gt;Frame&lt;/code&gt; has an event called &lt;code&gt;Navigated&lt;/code&gt; that can help us to write an extension method to get a reference to the actual instance:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enabling automatic updates for sideloaded UWP apps</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/update-sideloaded-uwp/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/update-sideloaded-uwp/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Recently we wanted to enable auto-updates for an app that we were developing for a client. The app is developed in UWP and it&amp;rsquo;s sideloaded into the client&amp;rsquo;s computers. Although Microsoft has added an auto-update functionality in the &lt;code&gt;1803&lt;/code&gt; build of Windows, we had a few issues with it:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;It was not very reliable&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;We didn&amp;rsquo;t have much control over it beside a simple auto-update policy that specified how often it should check for updates.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Troubleshooting was very hard as there were no clear way to find out why the auto-updater was not working properly.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;So I found &lt;a href=&#34;https://matthijs.hoekstraonline.net/2016/09/27/auto-updater-for-my-side-loaded-uwp-apps/&#34;&gt;an article&lt;/a&gt; from 2016 and decided to improve upon it and put it a &lt;a href=&#34;http://nuget.org/packages/Dwrandaz.AutoUpdateComponent&#34;&gt;nuget package&lt;/a&gt;. The library is open-source and is available on &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/dwrandaz/AutoUpdateComponent&#34;&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
